<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goka – Placeholders</title>
    <link>/goka/categories/placeholders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Placeholders on Goka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="/goka/categories/placeholders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Getting Started</title>
      <link>/goka/docs/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/goka/docs/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a placeholder page that shows you how to use this template site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information in this section helps your user try your project themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do your users need to do to start using your project? This could include downloading/installation instructions, including any prerequisites or system requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introductory “Hello World” example, if appropriate. More complex tutorials should live in the Tutorials section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider using the headings below for your getting started page. You can delete any that are not applicable to your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any system requirements for using your project? What languages are supported (if any)? Do users need to already have any software or tools installed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where can your user find your project code? How can they install it (binaries, installable package, build from source)? Are there multiple options/versions they can install and how should they choose the right one for them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any initial setup users need to do after installation to try your project?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-it-out&#34;&gt;Try it out!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can your users test their installation, for example by running a command or deploying a Hello World example?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
